[Music]
but our struggle does not stop
here failed
[Music]
fell
but we never lose our spirit
by continuing to innovate to
produce the best products wholeheartedly
collaborating
[Music]
without limits
Indonesia
[Music]
[Music] [
Music]
We are providing
greater benefits based on the Indonesian Provisions
[Music] same [Music]
[Music]
[Music] [Music] [
Laughter] [
Music]
[Applause]
Assalamualaikum warahmatullahi
wabarakatuh peace be upon us
all Shalom Om Swastiastu namo buddhaya
and greetings of virtue
Good afternoon let me introduce myself, I am
Andriansyah bermaby who will guide the
virtual xpose uirship scholarship and entrepreneurship webinar
Welcome to UI virtual xpose
is an annual export activity
organized by the
University of Indonesia graduate career development center CDC UI
under the Directorate of
graduate career development and alumni relations
in collaboration with
the University of Indonesia alumni association and career lab
as an information technology platform
job vacancies
March 2023 takes place from
March 6 to 18 and attended by
various well-known companies
on March 17 to 18 there
will be offline activities at the
UI hall,
the activities include bootcamp industry training
and company talks so that
participants can get to know the company
further and prepare themselves
In addition, my poem collaborates
with career left is a platform and
two and career Solutions that provide
support to fresh graduate students
and young professionals for
career preparation starting from making and evaluating
resumes career preparation classes and
job vacancies that are decorated for entry
level
careerlah also supports dozens of campuses
in Indonesia with a career management
platform for career centers and students
complete information about LED careers can be
accessed through website.com
next I would like to
thank the sponsors of wicisa
virtual Expo 22, namely Bank Danamon
Indonesia with the support of mufg as
one of the largest financial groups in the
world
Bank Danamon has local strength and
global expertise to provide
financial services and solutions for all customers
then there is PT Kereta Api Indonesia
Tbk
Paragon technology and Innovation the
largest local cosmetics company
in Indonesia which houses
well-known brands such as putri Wardah makeover
Emina kaos and
then there is PT Semen Indonesia Tbk
and also to our official media partners,
namely Kompasiana RTV  detik edu
kata data Metro TV Media Indonesia
mediacom.id suara karya.id narration
community narration Dahlia FM Bandung RTC
UI radio Tarumanegara University radio
Mercu Buana journalist news from Pasbana Island
and UNJ enter Club
Alright to all my friends
before we start the topic of this webinar,
please fill in the attendance by scanning
the barcode listed on the screen.
Next,
the topic of this webinar is How to
kick start your carrier
which will be presented by Kak Dwi Retno
Sekarwati
and Talent position senior Manager and
Kak Andrea Halim as agency program
development and coloring Manager from
SPD Insurance
before that Let's call
Kak Dwi and also Kak
Andrea Hello Kak Dwi
Hello good morning Hello
Alhamdulillah okay
Thank you for being given the opportunity
for today's session
okay okay before we start Kak Dwi
will
provide material about How to Kids
Okay thank you
in advance I want to make sure that my
friends who are here already
know what
FPD is a company maybe you can
give a reaction if you already
know what FWD is and I will
later ask my friends to
pay attention to the FWD company profile video
because after the company profile we will
have a session Q&A to find out
how far your
friends' knowledge about FPD is, okay,
next time you can share
[Music]
Okay, thank you.
Well, I want to know, friends, you
must have watched the video and
listened to what information
is in the FWD company profile video,
but before I give you the information, I
will repeat the information first, yes,
we at FPD focus on
customer needs so that we are supported by
technology and offer different insurance.
So if you
previously
knew that SWD was first attended
in 2014 with our tagline,
which carries the tagline, free
our steps, celebrate living, and we
are also the first insurance to provide
protection for extreme sports. Well, FWD
itself is in 10 countries. As
you have seen, FWD is in
Indonesia of course and also in
Singapore, Malaysia, Cambodia, the Philippines, the Philippines,
Hong Kong,
Macau, Japan, and Vietnam, so
Fede friends are in 10 countries and
we are strong in Asia. So if you
ask that FPD, what is it called,
uses digital as an
enabler to
change people's perspectives on
insurance. But we also, what is it called,
ensure that our service is  is
using or using human touch
where we Put our customer at the
center so we want to ensure that
customers who feel the experience with
fpd feel a different experience
with digital as an indibler okay well
I make sure my friends
watch or friends understand
the video that was previously delivered
about evd Well I also want to ensure
that in fpd we currently have 4
digital four distribution channels for
sales channels namely agency bank
insurance corporate care and digital
with its value everyday namely check
which is an abbreviation of
innovative commitment protective Open and carrying
to be able to ensure all employees in
employees in fpd to be able to
deliver the vision of fpd which is changing
or how to change the way
people think about society about
Insurance Well I want to make sure my
friends can answer in the chat
for the questions I convey
because there will be prizes from fwd for
friends who can answer
correctly Okay the first question fwd is present
in
10 countries in Asia I
want to ask for 5 countries only and the
fastest correct will get a prize
from fwd who can answer directly answer
in chat yes
no one has answered yet
maybe the prize is not attractive yes
friends
hello
Oh the sound is not stable okay now
may
Oh the chat is disabled can I ask my
friends from UI to be
able to chat in the chat column
Oh apparently there are many who might want to
answer but because it is disabled my friends
can't answer yet, friends from
UI moderator,
good for friends who want to
answer, maybe you can do it via the
Q&A chat box, okay
Okay while we're going, this is
one question, there is one question, so
later, friends who can answer
correctly, we will, what is it called,
inform the prize and
send the prize to friends
at UI Okay next, so friends,
we want to
share this with friends How are you,
friends, what are you called,
friends who have just graduated or
friends who are just starting
their careers to be able to
start your carrier So how
can you prepare yourself for the
future Okay next, the
first step that you definitely have to
do is make sure
your CV is updated
or you have made sure that all the
important information related to
yourself, related to your skills, related to what
your capabilities are, is all
in the CV, so make sure that when
you create the CV format, the
current one that is currently being done a lot
is the ATS CV format or
application applicant tracking system so
ATS friendly so make sure all
the information that you capture
in the CV is in accordance with
the needs, namely there is information related to
buyers in there is information related to what is
called your experience if
you don't have experience
you can include information related to
what is called internship related to
internship programs or related information
related to your experience organizing
an organization
organizing an
event in the organization Why is it
important to include it because from there
we can get an idea How are
your activities how are you in
your experience organizing something
Well if the CV is ready what do
you need to do is one you need
next to
optimize recruitment channels
recruitment channels what are they yes
friends if recruitment channels
now now want to make sure that
you have a Link in so what
information can you convey in the
Link in this Link is
like a CV so starting from
your education information information related to
your activities what are the names of
your abilities that you can convey
or you can include in the link
In so like the CV that you uploaded
into when you did the
job application process and K1 make sure you are
also
actively looking for information through the company
website so if you
now look more at the company website fpd
there are several that want positions and
When you are seen in  There is an
apply to start button that means
FPD uses ETS or ETS or
applicant tracking system so make sure
your application-APV is FTS
friendly enough Well, those are tips and tricks on
how you can optimize
recruitment channels and secondly,
when friends have used
Link in, then also explore the
career website of a company or
as I gave an example, the
website card, what are the things that are currently
viral at that time, make sure friends
also use or make sure from the
process side, friends, you will
be aware of what you have to
pay attention to, one internet email to your
friends' email, is your
friends' email active or secondly,
your WhatsApp number is also active, don't be suspicious
of unknown numbers
when they call you, who knows, those
are numbers from what's called
a recruiter or
when you get
a message via WhatsApp, don't immediately
block it, make sure you know first, what
is the content delivered by the person
who sent the message to
your WhatsApp number, Well, make sure
what is the name of your channel for
email and WhatsApp, your number is
all active, so those are the steps
you have to optimize Well, for the
next one,
if you have
sent or  Have you updated your CV? Then
you have explored the company,
currently the second position in a company,
make sure you ensure one email is
addressed. Well, when you process
sending what is called
your CV sent to an email,
make sure to mention the name,
for example, what is called a digital
graduate program, later make sure
there is your name there, then the
name addressed in the email is correct,
make sure and use
greetings, friends. Introduce
yourself, your background in the body of the email,
then also tell about
your activities, why are you fit to be able to
fill the position that has been veken, and
then also ask for that willingness to
review and the interview process, make sure your
name and number and
your cellphone number are active as
I said earlier. Well, if you
use or send to the career page,
make sure to read all the instructions
correctly, so if friends just
opened the career website,
there is How to apply or you have to
create a username first, make sure
one creative username, then what is called
apply using the Play button
in what is called in the career
website and make sure to read all
the instructions properly and correctly, there are no
missing points.
What is the name of the related information,
for example, related to career aspirations,
related information related to referrals,
reference numbers  or the names of who
can be contacted
Okay next,
after you
apply, the recruiter has reviewed
and the recruiter has invited you
for the interview process, make sure that in the
interview process you prepare yourself
well, an example of preparing yourself
well is what if you are
currently interviewing online,
make sure that
your internet connection is
reliable, friends, because
if the internet connection is not
good, the
recruiter will not be able to get
your information properly because
maybe there is or it could be the
mood of the interviewer himself, so it will be
uncomfortable because it is on off on
off, so one, make sure
your connection is good, second, the place, look for an
adequate place, not noisy, or if you
choose a coffee shop, choose a quiet coffee shop,
not crowded, friends, or
not in the mall, so zakat
is recommended, friends, look for a
quiet place and
good internet so that later when the
interview process is running, friends, you
will be able to interact with the recruiter
or with the interviewer optimally.
Well, after that, make sure that from what is
called
online, make sure that
your friends' pieces
represent yourselves
well if you want to
get what is called
in Persib by the recruiter as a person who is
what is called a
structure of people who  prepare yourself
well Make sure everything
I have said is prepared and
make sure you
can represent the meaning of Jester from the
appearance it will be
read like that to be able to
read it well okay
I think it is a should time I will
invite the
brothers from fpd to be able to help
me here because I want to invite
them friends to be able to see a
simulation of a brief overview in the
interview process and I can we will
give examples of what is recommended
and what is not recommended Why
so that friends can get
Inside yes because this is important for
friends for those who will Later practice a lot
for the interview process
and make sure this is one of the tips
and tricks before what is called the
interview process is done is to
practice okay Okay I will call sister
Shinta and sister Disti to help
me
for our roleplay today
Okay Disti and Sinta are recruiters from
fwd so remember yes her name is
Yasinta and the inscription ayudisti they
are
fpd who carry out the recruitment process well it is
also very important for friends
when in Link in you go back when
you see what the title is Talent
equation or when there is what is called the
status we are hiring or when
friends see the hashtag  we are hiring
or hiring or recruitment process
make sure Who is posting Well if
for example those who post are with the
title Talent equation means they
are the Pic in the company that is
conducting the recruitment process Okay I want to
simulate to be able to give an idea
to friends there will be three
common questions that are most
often asked by recruiters
during the interview process Okay are
you ready yet
Okay Sinta has immediately pointed out
the one who is not recommended and
Disti is the one who is recommended Okay
I will start the first question Okay
brothers and sisters like to know you better So
do you mind to introduce yourself okay
friends the interview maybe in the
interview can be in
English or in Indonesian Well
when the interview process is done in
English make sure you are also
ready by answering in
English Okay now we will
start the interview with Indonesian Okay I
want to get to know you better all brothers and
sisters so
we just introduce
yourselves so I get to know you
better okay Shinta yes Thank you
Ms. Dwi for your question slowly
I love from being a fresh
graduate from visiting the University of
Indonesia before I had
internship experience as a
startup that's probably just my experience
thank you
Okay earlier Sinta was the one who was not
recommended Okay now we
hear an example  which we can see
here is a recommended example
please sister
okay Hello thank you very much Mbak Dwi
for the opportunity to introduce once
again My name is
Disti I am a
graduate of the University of Indonesia
majoring in Psychology indeed for now
maybe I haven't got much
experience Mbak because of the procedure as well
but I have some
internship experience in a company
At that time I had an internship at a
startup company as an admin event
there I was responsible for
making
monthly reports in particular
and also helping the recruitment team
for sourcing and that was during
my college days Yes I also have a
lot of more happiness
for example there was a
sports event in
my company there I was responsible for
being the coordinator of course I also
helped to sell make a
competition schedule ensure the completeness of the
participant's documents and
as a sports coordinator like that
Mbak my experience hopefully can be
well received thank you Okay
friends now you know the difference Why is
Sis Sinta not recommended and
why is Sis Isti recommended Why is it because
from the answer Sis Sinta
this recruiter what's her name is
very
little information yes because Sis Cinta
only informed her name and where she
graduated from Well when earlier
explaining regarding introducing
herself we can get information
one
Kadis graduated from where second Adisti
what's her name  intensive in
what company and what did she do earlier
Sis Disti explained that she did the
recruitment process what is it called helping
the process and when there was a vacancy
what opportunities did she get In addition,
Sis Disti also informed
how when
she was in college what activities or
what activities did she participate in and the process there was any
experience What did she do
to organize an event
So from there we can get a
lot of information related to Sis
Disti being an interviewer or recruiter
getting an
active picture yes and how
resilient she is in facing
something okay
that was an example of one question
related to introducing yourself so
make sure when you introduce yourself
introduce yourself in a
structured way In what way and you
imagine How
the recruiter wants to know you make sure
you prepare yourself to answer
the question well then the
second question is a common one or
what is usually asked by recruiters
is
what do you know about fwd or
what do you know about the company you
want to apply for lafadz I will give an
example is what do you know
about fwd okay Sis Shinta
Okay thank you Mbak Dwi regarding SWD
as far as I know is
one of the insurance companies in Indonesia
thank you
now the question is the answer
recommended
Okay well previously I had the chance to open the
website of FPB,
it is a company engaged
in the insurance sector and it is more
common digital insurance, right, Sis,
because on the website it also sells
its products, there are also several
products that were sold on July 2nd on what is the name of
the website and the claim process is also
digital, Sis. Maybe that's all
I know about FPB.
If there is something wrong, I apologize.
Okay, Bing anus, friends. Well, why did
I give my opinion earlier, Sister
Shinta, it is not recommended. So Sister
Sinta doesn't want to  looking for not looking for
more information about evd
or the company that is being applied for
is being applied for well but if sister
Disti, she said the keyword is she is
looking for information on the website Because
now if you want to apply for a
company make sure one you know
what kind of company it is
so it can be seen How is the effort
from what is the name of the interviewer here
How far have you prepared yourself like
that it is very important to be able to
know what kind of
company you are applying for because it will be seen
one are you yourself in
terms of competence Are you also
suitable for the company that will be
the position that the company is looking for
okay that is a question related to
knowledge about the company then the
third is a question related to
challenges okay okay this is very common
Why are questions related to challenges
asked because usually recruitment is
how
from the interviewer when facing
a problem okay okay brothers Can
you tell or can you
give your experience
about what challenges do you
feel you According to you the
most difficult challenge and how did you
handle or overcome the challenge
Okay okay
so related to challenges
maybe Previously I had experienced
a challenge in my internet experience
at the previous company so
indeed there The number of teams there was not
too much so you could say I was
quite overwhelmed with the work
I held especially considering that at that time
I was a  still a student
and also new in the industry
so maybe that is one of
my biggest challenges so far
okay
sister Disti
Okay maybe the biggest challenge
I have ever experienced was when I did my
first internship at a startup Sis that
when I entered as an intern
there was also my supervisor and also
my two partners who were also
specialists there one month in the beginning
I was
taught a lot of new things especially about
recruitment but after one month it
turned out that the two
specialists in my team finally
chose to resign so in the end it was
just me and also my SPV at
that time this was definitely a
very big challenge for me because
at first I was there as an intern
I was also new to recruitment still had a
lot to learn and also of course
I still made a lot of mistakes in
my work but what I do
is I always try to list
down yes What do I need to
do today what do
I have to complete today so that I
can keep track with
my schedules for that day
to interview people or want to offer
people or maybe onboard people
like that So that's what I did and
after that finally because of STV I
saw that my performance was getting
better day by day Finally I was
appointed as a permanent employee at that
time like that Sis Okay  So
friends, you can see the
difference between Shinta and
Disti. So if Shinta only
informed that she was overwhelmed,
yes, but Disti
informed that she was a witness,
we got a picture of the
situation at that time, namely her position
was an intern or what is it called
in the recruitment team, there was no one there,
yes, there were lots of bags that were the
responsibility of those who were left behind
and Disti, what is it called Step Up, she
can take what is called the roll that is there
and she can show and can
answer the challenges given by
her Leader, so when there is a
success story, she also mentions it there,
so she tells the situation, she
tells how the condition was and she
tells the results. What is the result, she
was given or got the opportunity
to become a permanent employee, so it is very
important, friends, when you
convey what is called information or
describe the situation and what are the
results after that, the recruiter
or interviewer can get
a picture of your resilience in facing
a or facing a condition,
okay, that is an example of roleplay.
Well, to ensure that
your interview process is effective,
according to research from Mahreby
Rabian, there are three items, so 4, if
45%, that is voice tone and word are
factors.  most important besides
body movement so if online
body movement is sometimes a bit exciting
yes it is a bit difficult to see but
what is certain is that one thing
we must do is that it is absolutely mandatory
ethically is the camera must be on so that
body movement can be read, you know, the
text icon must be there even though online,
make sure your eyes are focused on the
camera, secondly, it is related to the Award and
voice Stone, so make sure it is stable, you
don't pause a lot, if it
becomes like that, it is also the basis
for assessment also for the
interview process, okay, okay, friends, the next thing
is to
make sure you also show respect
and appreciation because what is also
how we interact,
respect becomes value So how
in everyday life we ​​also have to
show respect, so in the
interview process, respect is also seen, yes,
friends, as conveyed by
voice Stone or Jester, it can be
assessed, well, for example,
and one more thing, when if he, if
we are in Indonesia, yes, in
eastern customs, we usually call him
with the embellishment of kakak or Mas or
mbak or Bapak or Ibu, so that can
also be used to show that
we respect, we appreciate
our conversation partner, okay, this is
also an important item for you to be able to
show
your personality as a
candidate or candidate who is
undergoing the interview process  next So
you have done all that
earlier you have made sure your Link in
updated your CV was updated made sure
before you
send the application you have
made sure one position is targeted is too what is it
called make sure what is it
called in the application process Is
your CV enough fts friendly well during the
interview process you have also what is it
called
to
describe yourself well
to the interviewer So if after
that the process is you want to be
applied by
the company or by fwd well
make sure one
of the existing processes is you build a
reputation So how do
we want to be known by someone's competence
is what is called a long-term investment
so if you later want to be
applied make sure you One build your
reputation also how do you buy your
personal branding you during the
interview process you can
communicate your vision or
your achievements earlier Like the
business brother earlier how far have we reached in
our process what is called roleplay he
conveyed What are the
projects he did
what are the activities and for you
also nurching your Network maintain
your good relationship with
the interviewer or in or when
you are in your current internship process and
intensive process or internship maintain
your good relationship with what are called
friends in the company
you are currently interning because when
later a  there is a chance that we
will definitely see friends who have
built or interacted with
us before or their network
already exists in the company So
if friends ensure that
friends maintain their network, it can
build
your networking in the future then
you also have to think positively and
be a
good person Okay next
if you haven't got your fortune or
haven't got it, don't be emotional, relax,
review and try again okay that's all the material
from me because next there will be
Andrea who will bring material
related to what is important for
you when your little brother already has an
income okay Andrea
hello friends
how many more minutes, yes,
can anyone give me an Inbox to chat
because if not I will also talk
If it's late until Eid
Propos asks for another 20 minutes, yes
brothers
Okay I'll try Try to be quick, yes
friends, yes Hello good morning
if he is good morning but if it's special
I want to talk it's morning, it means it's
time to wake up, yes, so let me introduce myself, I'm
Andre Hali, I got information that
most of the participants are
new graduates, some have just graduated and some are in their
final year, yes Well, that means
I'm very old, yes, so I'm also a
UI engineering graduate, but I  apostate from
my major but if apostate means
behind apostasy Actually there is repentance, yes,
repentance to my fashion so I've been
working at FB for 8 years I don't know why, huh Oh, I
just graduated that much, huh Yes, hello,
so I've been
working at FWD for 8 years, it's like
this, huh, what's the name of a
millennial who apostatizes,
it's really good, that's why I'm
still staying at FWD, today's
theme is about you
So how will you manage your money? I want to
ask my friends, can you please write in
the chat briefly? The
first question is, do
you guys feel like your
finances are healthy? Those who haven't
worked are okay, right? You guys get
income, you get income, you get snacks from your
parents. So, do you guys feel like
your finances are healthy or not?
If you're healthy, why? If you're not healthy,
why? Just mention one thing, do
n't share here, I can't
help much, if you're
not healthy, can you please help me to be
healthy in a way, huh, the question is,
this question is, this question is from
after the trial with the supervisor,
what are the standards?  Sis, the standardization
according to your friends, yes, according to
your friends, is it healthy or
not? This question
has been completely discussed by the supervisor,
it seems like you can try to see, I want to
test this and do a small survey,
unhealthy because the income is smaller,
expenses Oh, I don't know,
actually, sometimes healthy, sometimes
unhealthy, maybe because you stay up late,
Miss Anisa, the Hombing, so you do
n't get enough rest, so sometimes healthy,
sometimes unhealthy, and then no, because you buy
too many snacks, not because I don't like
that, the others have different
stories, so this is it. Why is
this question interesting for me, friends? Because
for my friends, I asked my friends,
I also still have contacts with juniors
in UI engineering, so I asked both those who have
just graduated, yes, to any major,
the question is about your finances, are you healthy or
not? Then I asked my
college friends, friends at the office, many of
whom are older, and so on, Baduy
and none of them answered healthy,
yes, my finances are very healthy, so
the conclusion, friends, is that
healthy finances don't have the same effect
as salary, so if
you want to
start a new income, it turns out that those who
have been around for dozens of years, if you are asked about
finances  Baduy healthy or not,
the answer is definitely like that, so it has nothing to
do with salary, so
the question may be, how do you determine whether your
finances are healthy or not, so
there are actually 4 indicators, my finances or
not, there are many indicators,
yes, the standardization or
so-called indicators, yes, I will share
only 4 and quickly because this is also
usually on the internet, okay, next, the
first is that friends must have an
emergency fund of 3-6 times
monthly expenses, so for example, if friends
spend 2 million monthly, now
that means friends must have at least
6 to 12 million,
that's easy, right? 3 to 6 times,
friends, this emergency fund expenditure was
really felt during the pandemic,
especially for people who work,
yes, people who work whose money is
cut from their salary or even laid off,
Well, it's just to feel it, yes, and it's so
important, if yesterday,
the question is
in what form it must be in the form of a
deposit or not, it must be in
another form, it must not be in the form of gold, it must not be in the form of mutual funds, it must not be in the form of
shares, it must not be in a
form whose value fluctuates, it will go up and down,
up and down, it must
not be
okay  The second one is allowed next then the second
is friends must have a minimum
every month come on this does not need to be answered
yes Do all friends here
save at least 10% of the minimum income
So if for example friends
pocket money 3 million or 5 million means
10% of it That's the second healthy condition
or not allowed next because this is a theory well
look at the maximum consumption of 15%
of income if the installments are productive
That means it can be 3-30% of income
consumer installments are consumer installments that
decrease in value friends make installments
or something that decreases in value
for example
installments for Skincare, does the value
decrease or not yes face is like that yes face is an asset
that decreases or an asset that increases well
that is allowed Try to answer yourselves
in your heart or if it is productive
productive means that the asset's
value increases so it can be up to 30% of
this income If the
last installment is the fourth then
friends usually will definitely work later will
this Yes will collect money later the
money will be used to buy something hopefully
something productive well later when
finished productive  This will change
into what is called wealth, it's
clean. This is ours, from
this wealth, there are no more debts, for example,
I bought a cellphone, this cellphone
costs, for example, it's easy to make it easy,
10 million to make it easy, 10 million of
this 10 million I bought it in the form of
0% installments. Well, I've paid installments for 6 months,
meaning my assets have paid half of it.
From 12 months, that means
half of my assets, you could say 5 million, that
doesn't include this, yes, the value has decreased. Well,
friends,
friends, there must be
assets in the form of immovable assets,
there are assets used personally,
there are assets that grow,
other assets that increase, well, friends,
at least 50% of your friends' assets
must be in the form of investments, meaning
the value moves up, yes, sometimes it
goes up, sometimes it goes down, like property, sometimes it goes up, sometimes it goes down,
but it tends to go up,
gold also tends to go up, not tend to
go down, for example, a car.
Well, that's friends, 4 4 site theories only.
Then the question is, what
if friends, when you get money, that's an
indicator, for example, like
friends, check your blood, how
can you be called healthy, yes, that
means  The cholesterol should be so much
then the sugar from so many days the uric acid
should be so much and so on
the way is the question is
How to do it, namely here I give the best practice called 3 post casual so imagine friends when you get income, your income is divided into 3 so don't make it just one One office but friends converted to Islam into three Well, the first is it allowed
next well, friends,
this income income means it can be a salary for
friends who have worked and are
safe or pocket money Well,
friends, from all that is obtained, it is
divided The first is a
maximum of 60% for current needs
so the needs that when
friends spend money are indeed
to buy current needs
monthly money electricity is an example for
people in general, later
friends can adjust it themselves for
me who is a flash graduate or still in the
final semester, how is it
now, for example, friends, the need
for photocopying and so on,
eating WiFi then transportation to campus
Then again, those
are current needs, a
maximum of 10% is separated So if it is
from 5 million, it means that 3 million can be
used for the current maximum, meaning
if it is more  It's
so bad, the second one, don't forget
there's the present, the second one is next, there's the
future,
eee, maybe friends, there are cheats,
three examples of college, children, retirement, and
desires, maybe for friends
now, it's not related, it's not related,
retirement is still far away, it's still
very far away, I can't imagine it, it's not
related to children's education funds
or it's not related to
other desires,
I was once young, yeah, of course, I was once young, I
graduated, I really know how it feels to be desperate,
desperate to get my first salary and want it, at
that time, I was,
one of my regrets is,
if I could turn the machine
back to time, I would start
saving, not saving, yes,
saving for my future desires, at
that time, you could say 90% of my money was spent
on the present, everything, so the
third one is
this score, it's not continued, friends, what can I do
for the present, well, friends, it
's
for gold deposits, mutual funds, stocks,
property, other investment instruments
for friends who might still be
limited,
please open the mutual fund, I
don't mention what, friends, you can
look for it yourself, that's when I open IG, there are
lots of ads,
Jerome Polin's ads  That's what's appearing a lot
on fpip, right? Well, that's an example
of the most friends investing
but affordable investment and safe, right?
That's for future needs,
next, let's continue, this is the remaining minimum of
10%, that's for precaution, right,
I want to highlight this just in case,
friends, because it's often forgotten,
often
forgotten So the concept of just in case is
like this, friends,
if you imagine a car, there
's an
airbag in it, right, then there's also Banser,
when friends buy a car, one day
you can buy a car,
ask friends, write in the chat, answer
quickly, friends, do you want a car
that has Banser and
airbags or not, it's okay,
friends, get a car that doesn't have an airbag or
doesn't have a banser,
the answer is, do you want it or not, there's an
airbag or not, of course,
you want it, right, others also want it, I
also want it, if I buy it, don't let it not have one,
okay, can you stop the second question,
friends, do you want to use the airbag or
not?
Now you can answer, do you want to use it or
not,
friends, do you want to use it or
not, God forbid? Don't let it happen  use
it exactly friends just in case it
is exactly the same concept as RB
we have to have but we
use it yes Well the first thing in just in
case is this is what is called insurance
friends
yes that is the first thing to take care of
inpatient nurses inpatient nurses that means
if friends are admitted to inpatient care,
yes, enter the room, don't let the
money come from your own money like that
first the second is allowed next the second
is critical illness so like this don't
confuse inpatient care friendly benefits
with critical illness if friends are
admitted understand not friends are
sick because they have to have chemotherapy the
hospital costs will be paid later
fwd will pay that means I
have inpatient insurance
so all the hospital costs
will be paid but friends when
I have to God forbid I get cancer and
have chemotherapy I may not necessarily
have the energy to work in fwd
because they say like going to therapy is
tiring just sitting is tiring
so I may not necessarily be able to work DBD
finally I had to decide to resign
well the question when I decided
to resign Who should pay for
food Andre Halim also wants to watch
netflix also wants
The laptop keeps changing every 5 years
Well, friends, that's the insurance disease, that's
compensation, later on, friends,
one M1 is up to you for what, it doesn't have to be
for hospital costs. That's one of the
waters, I'll use it for living expenses.
Well, that's why friends,
critical illness insurance is there to
cover living expenses, not hospitalization costs, don't do it the
other way around, don't do it the other way around, to
pay for medical expenses, that's not it, the
third one, this is the third one, maybe the one that's
pa  ling is not related to friends, namely
insurance that provides benefits for
early death, this is usually for people who
are married who have dependents, such as
having children, having a wife who does not
work, for example, or a wife and husband who
work, their children are still small.
Don't let it happen that when you die, you
have to ask for money from other people. Well,
the question of these 3 is that, that's
the theory of best practice,
the question is, if for example, this is
how, how should it be a priority?
Well,
the answer, friends, is like this, if
this is just in case there is no more, then like it or
not, the future, if
for example, we have to always remember
then enter through this,
like it or not, we will take money
that can be sacrificed, namely our deposits, we
sell gold, we sell our mutual funds, we
liquidate everything, we liquidate property, we
sell, we need money and so on,
the question is, actually, it is
bought for the future, meaning the
next future no longer exists, right?
But okay, okay, it turns out that the
future of money can still be sought,
that is, if it is enough, if it is still not enough, you can
next time,
if it is still not enough, it's okay, but
the question is, if it is still not enough,
how should it be, well, that's the next one, friends.
That's why these 3 must be a priority, it
doesn't have to be  the presentation is the same 6310 but
there is a
list if friends it turns out that I
also first 90% is the present 90% Well,
at least the future 5% just
in case 5% after that slowly
fix it like that well like that
friends so everything must be a
priority
until the pocket money what is it called 5 million
expenses then 20 million Because
this 15 million we add more like that
don't let it happen
Okay next yeah well
this Coincidentally just appeared
Andrea Halim's financial regrets
I think this should not be on the
internet because this is me who experienced it
myself and I regret I have
fallen like that yes ups and downs about
finances okay next the first
credit card I don't know what it's
like nowadays But when I was in the past it felt like
if I had a credit card especially the
black Go one like that oh that was really cool yeah
I don't know if it's still relevant or not
now most people work
credit cards want to use and I
think credit cards are
extra money the danger is friends
when friends make transactions for people
who don't like to take notes like me I don't
realize how many transactions I've made with a
credit card then get the limit  When I was growing up, I was
given a big one by
the bank and finally I was
trapped for how many months, 6 months,
6 months or more, I was only
able to pay, I
couldn't pay it off, so I
can say that I only paid the
minimum payment and friends should
know that credit cards have
really big interest, 36% a year, well that's the
first regret, be careful if you want to have a
credit card, please, but it's not
extra money, friends, use it
for convenience, okay,
secondly, people's opinions are more important,
come on, who has it?
Who has it? Why do friends
have a corps circle, is it because of function
or because of prestige, be careful
Now I'm used to not
caring about people's opinions, the t-shirts I
wear, I always wear black t-shirts, I
never wear any other colored clothes, I
don't buy them at those
branded stores, I buy
original
Tokopedia, it only costs 35 thousand and
I buy 10 of them for a year, it's
more important not to let friends
prioritize other people's opinions because it's
not important, but that's
for me, I feel like what's the point of
getting validation from other people just
because of fashion, because things like
South Korea and  others the third
impulsive buying impulsive buying this
means friends when you buy
straight away buy it without thinking is there a
cheaper one yes Is
there an alternative Is the item
really needed or not Well don't
think about that so straight away buy it
That's the third eh the
fourth well friends I work in
insurance you could say from the beginning of my career
I just graduated then Oh yeah
there was a discount victim of a promo straight away
Promo like that want to buy While there is a
discount when bought Oh my the item is not
used that is also careful that includes
me sure
Well I went back I bought I worked in an
insurance company from the beginning of my career
But unfortunately I just bought the insurance
2 years ago yeah
I just bought the insurance 2 years ago
don't be like that because training is
expensive
then the next when I
started to fix this why my finances
only invest I invest only in
one instrument that
instrument is at that time I invested a lot
in deposits that are included in
investment instruments that are very slow be
careful don't just invest in one
instrument or here have you
ever been a victim of crypto Hopefully not
yes that is also an example when we
invest in one instrument so
friends
when I get used to investing in gold in
mutual funds if I can pay off
property in installments Wow, that's great, please, the
important thing is to divide it and lastly,
I never share it, that's a
big mistake that I prevent, I never
share it so I think I took
the money here from one pocket
only, so I don't know Oh, it turns out
I never
paid attention to my future needs because it was used up for the present, that's
why friends, this is the
last slide, actually there are still slides, but
because there's not enough time,
I'll just end it. The important thing is that
some important points, friends, you have
got my message, divide it into 3 to the present post
60% because Believe me, if friends
say but my pocket
money salary is not enough, my first salary is
still small, believe me, people
whose income is 20 million also have the same answer,
but their salary is still not enough, later it will be 30
million but their salary is not enough, well, that's the
skin thing,
because I'm used to continuing to increase my
lifestyle, continue to increase it, so divide it
into
360% for the present, a maximum of at least
30% for the future, and 10% for
emergencies. Well, that's it, friends. Thank you. That
means now I  hand it over to the
UI team, thank you
Okay, thank you to Ms. Dwi and
also Kak Andrea for the presentation that
really inspired us all regarding
insurance that was delivered by
the next
for friends, it is
reminded again for those who have not
filled in the attendance, please fill in the attendance
first by scanning the
Barcode that is on the screen, you
can make sure that the friends who
have answered earlier, we will give
prizes to friends who answer
correctly and the earliest,
yes, the fastest, yes,
then
we will
work together with careers and
friends can visit the website
uicc.co on the website there are
hundreds of job vacancies with
various companies that
friends can apply for in addition to the
work on the
laptop, there are also training and
webinars that friends can follow
for free, of course, at this event
we are opening the opportunity for friends
who want to get the Grand Price of
Garuda tickets Jakarta Bali and Jakarta Lombok
for more complete information, please
visit Instagram
and also Tik Tok
Okay, thank you very much for the material
and presentation delivered by Kak
Dwi and also Kak Andrea, which is certainly
very interesting and useful regarding
Effendi insurance which has a commitment
to changing people's perspectives
on Insurance and with the support of
digital technology
Next to the speakers and
also Everyday Insurance
after this, please leave the
Zoom room and for friends,
please stay in this Zoom room
because next we will
hold a shift school session with a
scholarship to Ireland
after this I would also like to
thank the sponsor UI, it is
still allowed
Why Miss if we
[Laughs]
mentioned that we have a feedback form
for this event from FWD Insurance, please
share it with other friends,
okay,
before we close the webinar
this afternoon, there will be a feedback session that
will be given by
maybe Miss Anisa, may you send the
link
Okay, the committee has sent the
feedback link that can be filled in regarding the
webinar session this afternoon,
next I would like to
thank the virtual sponsor
Expose
with the support of MUFG as one of the
largest financial groups in the world, Bank
Danamon has local strength from
Global expertise to provide
financial services and solutions for all customers
and also there is PT Kereta Api Indonesia Tbk
Paragon technology
PT Semen Indonesia Tbk
and also to our official media partner,
namely good news from Indonesia
media Tifa Tanimbar, startup friends, UKM
entrepreneurs, UB
lokernesia.id info webinar.event Depok
24 hours event lockers dotlist internship
Jakarta lockers  jakarta.id escort
events Ina lokernas.com
student catalyst
friends who want to send
job applications Please contact please
visit the website at
https./
uic.com because there will be hundreds of
job applications that might be your soul mate
In addition,
friends can join
other UI 2023 webinars because there will be a total of 52
webinars until Tuesday,
March 16, 2023
every day from 9:30 am to
4 pm
Once again I would like to thank
Kak Dwi and also Kak Andrea
as our speakers this afternoon
and also to all other participants of the
uichise virtual xpose
2023 webinar
greetings to all of us Greetings of
health and thank you
[Music]
[Music] [
Applause]
[Music] the
largest building materials solution provider in the region
we create future construction methods
that are fast,
affordable and environmentally friendly
we innovate by creating
more practical,
integrated and useful construction facilities
[Music]
Assalamualaikum  warahmatullahi
wabarakatuh peace be upon us
all Shalom Om Swastiastu name culture
greetings of virtue Good afternoon let me introduce myself,
I am Andreansyah birmabi who will
guide the UE cisee career
internship scholarship and
entrepreneurship virtual export webinar 2020
Welcome to the channel
organized by the
graduate career development center of the University of
Indonesia CDC UI under the Directorate of
graduate career development and
alumni relations UI in collaboration with the
alumni association of the University of Indonesia and career
lab as a job vacancy information technology platform
its activities include bootcamp industry training
and companies so that participants
can learn more about companies
and prepare themselves for the career world
more complete information can be visited
through the website uicc.carilap.com
In addition, my test collaborates with
career lab career lab is a platform and
to and career Solution that provides
support to fresh graduate students
and young professionals for
career preparation starting from the creation and evaluation of
resumes career preparation classes as well as
job vacancies that are accurate for
entry level more complete information about
carilab please access the website
Next we would like to
thank the sponsor uichisaver
there is Bang Danamon Indonesia with
the support of mwfg as one of the
largest financial groups in Indonesia Bank
Danamon has local strength and
Global expertise to provide
financial services and solutions for all customers
and also there is PT Kereta Api Indonesia Tbk
Paragon Technology and Innovation the
largest local cosmetics company
in Indonesia which houses
well-known brands such as putri Wardah makeover
Emina
instaperfect t-shirts and
also there is PT Semen Indonesia Tbk
as well as to our official media partners
namely Kompasiana RTV detik edu kata
data Metro TV Media Indonesia
metcom.id suara karya.id narasi
komunitas narasi Dahlia FM Bandung RTC
UI radio Universitas Tarumanegara radio
Mercu Buana journalist news Pulau pas
Bana and UNJ entrepreneur Club
Okay before we enter
this webinar for friends who have not
done the attendance please scan the barcode
that has been listed on the screen
In addition to the uicsay event
for friends who want to get
the chance to take home the Grand Price of
Garuda tickets Jakarta Bali and Jakarta Lombok
friends can Check Instagram
@karilab and also Tik Tok
Okay before we start
this webinar who will be with us here
is Mbak Miranda
Hello Mbak Miranda Hello
Sis good afternoon
Good afternoon Mbak Miranda How
are you today Alhamdulillah healthy
Sis this may be the video disabled by the
host like  I can't Click it's
okay
it's impossible to
reactivate the video
great Good afternoon Sis Alhamdulillah healthy
Sis how are you I Alhamdulillah
healthy too Sis
Okay
Airline the making of you which will be
presented by Ms. Miranda as the
education leader from education in
Airlines without further ado to
Ms. Miranda time and screen
are welcome
Thank you Sis Good afternoon
friends all, I hope you are
always in good health let me introduce my name, Ms.
Miranda Hog without further ado Sis
will try to share information about
Why should you study in Ireland
Is it visible Sis the moderator
is visible Sis
Good afternoon friends in Indonesia
welcome to Ireland
before I start my presentation this afternoon
I will play a little video
about Why should you choose
Ireland
[Music]
all
[Music] [
Applause] [
Applause]
[Music]
Maybe a little about education Island
for friends who may not
know that
education in island is
under the auspices of the Ministry of Higher Education in
Ireland we were assigned by
our Minister of Education minus to
promote our 27 Universities in
Indonesia
a little about Ireland maybe
friends also don't know
Ireland is famous as a country
which is safe and friendly and we are the
only English speaking country in the
European Continent we are also part
of the European Union Therefore
our currency is Euro our capital is in
Dublin the second largest capital is in the
city of chord the third is in the city of golwei and the
fourth is in the city of limrik the population of
Ireland is only 5 million 5 million
yes friends we are also famous for excelling
in the field of education a country that is
known for being creative and innovative and also
has a high cultural taste the
company in the field of IT Pharma is the
head office is also in Ireland you know
friends well what is even more interesting
you as an international student
are allowed to work part time
while studying in Ireland
for 20 hours you can work during the
lecture period and 40 hours during the holiday period
in this part time work opportunity
you will be paid 11 Euros 1 hour
what is also no less interesting is the rest is
free yes friends for
Indonesian citizens tourists and students
You are also given permission to
work in Ireland after
completing your studies for those who
complete their undergraduate studies the study period for S1 is
one year for S2 and S3 2 years
Ireland is also nominated by Lonely
planet as the top country
to visit you friends
you can see from  pictures of
our beautiful words and also the
scenery
in 2022 in the global kiss index
Ireland also
sits at number 3 yes
friends as a very
safe country and
transportation in Ireland for
big cities there may
be buses and trains yes friends but
maybe for other small cities
maybe more often used
vehicles such as bicycles
for the main airport is in
Dublin then there is also in the city of Shannon
how many institutions are there Sis
if friends look at our map
Ireland is indeed centered in the capital
in Dublin also Sis said the
second largest capital is in the city of chord
and the third largest capital is in the city of
gawai and the fourth is in the link but
don't worry throughout Ireland there are
many Indonesian students Sis
how many PTN in Ireland we have
8 sorry this Maybe a typo there are 8 PTN
in Ireland including technology
indeed if you look at the list it is
indeed centered in
our capital in
what are the requirements Sis to be
able to study in Ireland if for S1
on average all accept from SMA 3 and
also those who ID Then for those who want to
complete their masks in Ireland
are accepted from buchele abroad or
S1 and type 4  Maybe you also want to
convey that for the Master on that floor it's
only one year for the English profession
you have to have iOS
but also many of our PTNs and institutions
accept 2 Linggos,
what are the most popular majors, Sis, by
Indonesian students in Ireland,
if you look here, 10 courses
for Ireland are indeed
closely related to ICP, yes, So there are
computer science analytics data and
so on, but don't worry, we have
more than 5,000 programs offered by
institutions in Ireland,
how much is it to study in Ireland, Sis, this is just a
general overview, friends, for
the cost of studying in Ireland, but don't
worry, many of our institutions and
universities also provide
scholarships for the
most awaited, of course, there are
scholarships, right, Miranda,
there are, we have one that is
currently open and will close
at the end of the month, you can check
the information through the
following ocean for S1, S2 and S3,
then of course you can also
see on our website education Island
for S1, S2 and S3, maybe the scholarships from
each institution in Ireland are
only a large part, friends,
maybe not written But there are also
several institutions that provide
full scholarships and S3,
then of course because we are part of the
European Union, friends, you can also apply
for  Erasmus plus program or
Erasmus Mundus
of course we are
also happy to include choosing Isma, friends
Well, on the Isma list this year are
University
and University of go away for
friends who may be in
vocational school, you can apply for Iis mah
vocational
this year there is Shannon college Hotel
Management and download technology for
lecturers You can also apply
through Indonesian education scholarships
and of course also through LPDP
How much is the cost of living in Ireland,
this is an estimate from
Indonesian friends in Ireland,
friends Well, this includes costs, this
includes
accommodation, your HP company,
internet and also shopping, of course, this
also affects the city you
will choose later I am
also very happy to
share that we have PPI
Ireland, friends, they have been
established since 2013, please follow
PPI Ireland's Instagram and also email
to friends if you have further questions,
as I have said before,
after completing your studies, you
are allowed to work in Ireland
Ireland is also known as the
Balinese silicon of your
companies Of course, it is
no longer foreign to the eyes some time
ago, TikTok also opened
its European headquarters  In Ireland,
from this map, we can see
where these companies come from,
friends.
What's no less interesting is that in
Indonesia there is also an Irish Embassy. From what
I said, the visa for
Indonesian citizens is free and the
student visa process takes about 8 weeks. But
I also need to say that the
Irish visa is only valid for entry to
Ireland, friends. It is not
valid for entry to the UK or the
European Union.  Other pa
of course also follow my Instagram
Ireland in Ireland in Indonesia
for example yes Sis I think Europe is maybe a
little bit if from Jakarta Usually
we tell
international students to fly via
Dubai it's 8 hours then continue
the trip to
Dublin or about 8 hours also
for more information friends can
see on our website at education in
island.com all information is available
there Why should you study in Ireland
How can you study and
what courses are offered
of course also don't forget please what
please also follow us on education
Instagram because there are lots of
interesting info sessions and also
of course scholarship info
okay that's all the presentation from sister here
is my contact in Indonesia you
can WA or SMS
email also Yes please and of course
follow our Instagram maybe for
friends who still use
Facebook You can also follow
Facebook education in island
Okay
thank you
Okay thank you to Sis Miranda
for the material that has been delivered is
very interesting yes of course
friends about studying in Ireland
with a scholarship of course well I
remind friends again for those
who want to ask about
scholarships or about education
in Ireland can
write in the cnibox column
Okay we have got one question
Sis
Okay maybe I'll just read it right away yes
sis  Yes
Okay well here is a question from
Rendy Aris Fajrin Kak Miranda Is it possible
if you already have a Master's degree
Can you register for CEOs
Okay maybe to Kak Miranda,
please Thank you sis thank you
sis Rendi the question is of course you can still
register for
but maybe you have to be a little faster,
Kak Rendi because the deadline is
March 25th, yes But stay enthusiastic
if you have any questions, you can directly
WA Kak Miranda too
Okay Okay Well, that means there is still a
chance until March 25th
to Kak Rendi and also to
friends of course for those who want
to register for government Airlines
okay well Here is another question, Kak
maybe a follow up question from Kak
Rendy, it seems like you are very interested,
the question is the plan is around
June or July there will be an announcement
regarding the scholarship for the
next timeline, what is it like, Kak
and when will you leave, Kak Miranda
Okay okay to Kak Miranda,
please be
enthusiastic, Kak Rendy, I think he is a scholarship fighter,
Kak Yes,
maybe around June, July, August,
maybe, or even before, but
to start studying in September,
Kak Rendy, so if you have
received
acceptance from the Irish government,
then you will have to apply for
a visa, of course, yes, as you
said  in the presentation it takes 8
weeks so
if Rendy is one of the
selected ordi later please can you contact me
can you help me to contact the
Irish ambassador in Jakarta
maybe I
also want to comment on this Sis Fauzia Sorry
Sis Fauziah Sis you spoke too
fast
Sorry yes later you can WA me
directly if you have other questions
Okay Okay well according to the answer that
we have given to Sis Rendy
earlier there is still an opportunity like that so
immediately register and also immediately
prepare the necessary files
next there is one last question
Sis from Keadilan Kresna Good
afternoon Sis, let me introduce myself my name is Dean is it
permissible to take a Masters with a
different major in Ireland Oh yes I
want to ask Sis about tolerance
between religions especially Islam there
Then regarding the learning culture Can it be
said to be safe That's all and
thank you in advance to us You are
welcome earlier The
questions
First, is
choosing a Masters major with
different choices Oh different study programs Yes I mean it's
allowed no problem then
also regarding religion yes
religious tolerance yes thank God if Sis
Miranda may say
in Ireland there is an association
called  Firdaus Ireland Sis so indeed
Islam is also highly respected
many
Irish citizens are also
Muslims yes And maybe there are not
as many mosques as in Indonesia but in
the capital there is one in Dublin then in the court there
are also then PPI friends also
often hold gatherings
to read the Quran and so on yes
so there is no need to worry about the
last one Is
for the last question
related to the learning culture is said to be safe
quite safe yes very safe yes like
before Maybe seen in the
presentation we are ranked third in
the world as the safest country
if you can also share
yesterday's friends Isna Yes maybe
you also know yes Sis moderator there is
Isna who under the Nadine program
our independent campus has accepted more than 50
Indonesian students from all over
Indonesia under the Islamic program and
if you follow them on
Instagram they really feel it is fun
yes studying in Ireland maybe it is also a bit
different like in Indonesia the lecturer
in Ireland is like a friend maybe
more accessible according to
alumni friends Isna Yes sis moderator
that's what you heard is like
that
Okay well it turns out there are more
questions Sis some questions and
it seems interesting too from
Sis Fauziah Isma Daulay I want to
ask is it necessary or not  Sis, before
we study abroad, we have
savings
of course Sis, of course you have to
have savings, well, this is also
one of the visa requirements that
international students must have
If I'm not mistaken, 10,000 Euros, right,
moderator in savings to show
their living expenses while in Ireland
And this also applies to
other European Union countries And also maybe
other countries, yes, because
it also definitely helps for
living close We are there
Okay, next, Sis, there is a
question, maybe this is from Anonymous
athendi, we don't know who, but
the question is, Sis, my GPA is not
up to 3, but I already have
work experience and several organizations,
is it still possible to enter the
Island government scholarship
Oh yes, it seems there is a standard, Sis,
moderator, for the GPA, yes, if I'm not
mistaken, the JPE must be 4, if I'm not mistaken,
if Sis Miranda remembers correctly,
maybe you can just try it, Sis, the
important thing to look at is actually
from the government scholarship advertisement,
it's the personal statement, right,
like the moderator, that's important,
then there are also several other things,
like
you might be active in campus
CSR and so on. That's also
quite a high voice, later, Sis, I can
help you  If you want help with
personal statements and so on,
please just WA me later.
Maybe friends who are
really curious about scholarships and
have plans to take a
scholarship to Ireland can really
contact this camera. Well,
next, Sis, there is a question from
Yuliana
about culture shops, Sis, which are
often experienced by Indonesian students
studying in Ireland. Is there a
student community in Ireland and what are
their activities?
Yes, I often hear this from
Indonesian friends about culture shock,
maybe if
Yuliana, Sis, can you share culture shops
for Indonesian student friends?
Maybe it's more about the weather, Sis, the air,
Sis, Yulian, because it's cold right now.
Maybe if Sis, Yuliana, the moderator,
and other friends see that in Europe it's
snowing now, which should be
spring and heading towards summer,
maybe that's what's suitable, Sis, you have to be
prepared to
have a thick jacket, a thick hat, and
thick socks, maybe that's more about the
air.
Student communities like Sis, as I
mentioned earlier, there's PPI Ireland, right?
Well, they also have quite a
lot of activities because every
month there's definitely a gathering. And
they're not only in the capital,
Sis, Yuliana, they're in the city, they're in the city.
aflon and so on so don't be
afraid of homesickness they will always
accompany you
Well that's right, it means there are quite a
lot of Indonesian students
or Indonesians who
are traveling to Ireland
Okay Well next Sis, there is a
final question from Sis Emilia PM
regarding Are there any programs like
Summer programs or short courses in
Ireland and Are there any scholarships for
that Sis
Amelia There are many Summer programs or Shortcuts,
Sis, maybe I can't
mention them one by one here later Sis
Emily, you can PM me I just remember that I
was at UCD, there was at University,
on average, there must be Sis with
the family but for
scholarship information, maybe we have to be a
little bit skin, we have to find out, we have to do research
for Emilia If you want, Sis Emilia
can WA Sis too
Oh yes, you mainlanders, maybe you can
join in advertising a little at the end of
that month, later on the date, wait
a minute, on
March 25th and 26th, you are organized in 2023
from half past one to 5 pm,
there is an exhibition at Polman Jakarta
Central Park, Sis, so there are two
institutions from Ireland that will participate,
so please register all  the info is
on our Instagram yes Sis moderator
maybe later friends who really
seem like Ireland is really exciting
maybe you can directly consult
directly with the two institutions that will
come directly from Island thank you okay okay Well that's
right
friends who are really curious
and want to continue their studies in
Ireland can really come to the
event of Sis Miranda which will be
held at the tournament
in Central Park yes friends in
Slipi
Thank you very much for the material and
presentation that we have carried out
with Sis Miranda about scholarships
which are very interesting and useful Well
we now know friends about
How to get a
scholarship to a university in
Ireland Well next
Once again I remind
friends who want to who have not
filled in the attendance please fill in the attendance
first by scanning the barcode
on the screen
Okay Next we would like to
thank again the
sponsors of uicy savertual export 2020, namely
Bank Danamon Indonesia with
the support of mufg as one of the
largest financial groups in the world Bank Danamon
has local strength and
Global expertise to provide financial services and
solutions for all customers and
also from PT Kereta Api Indonesia
Tbk and Paragon Technology and
Innovation company  The largest local cosmetics company
in Indonesia which houses
well-known brands such as Putri Wardah
makeover Emina
instaperfect t-shirts and crystaller and there are
also from PT Semen Indonesia Tbk
and also to our official media partners,
there is good news from Indonesia
media Tifa Tanimbar startup friends UKM
entrepreneurship UB
lokernesia.id info webinar.event Depok
24 hours loker event dotlist
magang.jakarta loker jakarta.id escort
events Ina lokernas.com and also
student catalysts
next for friends who want to
register themselves regarding
job vacancies and internships friends
can visit the website
ui.com because on the website
there are hundreds of job vacancies
with various well-known companies well
besides jobs also on
website.carilab.com there are also
various training and webinars that
friends can do for free
and reminded again for
friends who are interested and also want to
get the chance to take home the Grand
Price of Garuda tickets Jakarta Bali and
Jakarta Lombok friends can
take part in the competition by exploring
Instagram
@karilame.co.id
Okay, I would like to thank
Kak Miranda as a speaker at the
webinar  this afternoon and also to
all participants who have attended the
scholarship talk webinar this afternoon
see you in the next 2023 webinar
best wishes to all of us Greetings of
health and thank you
[Music]
[Music] [
Applause]
[Music]
hahaha less makes your life
complicated Sis now there is a
payment option at Kai easier
and faster access pay using kaipai buy tickets
from ban have to open many top applications
then your kaipai balance to be able to
enjoy payments on all Kai features
access without transaction fees if there is an
easier and cheaper way I would
prefer him to pay for it in a link access
in just one click make your life
more relaxed use Kip DKI simple access
[Music]
from a belief we have succeeded in
realizing many big dreams
but our struggle does not stop
here
failed
fell
Noah challenges
but we never lose enthusiasm
by continuing to innovate to produce the
best products wholeheartedly
collaborate
[Music]
create Without Limits
developing Potential is our way
Keep Running
since 2019 we transformed
into Paragon Core which consists of
Paragon  Indonesian technology
and paramag Global inspira as a
distribution company
we have 41 distribution centers
more than 10,000 paragonians and we
will continue to grow
with the largest arena center
in Indonesia we continue to innovate
to produce the best brands
[Music]
Our vision is to provide
greater benefits
based on 4 pillars to help others
for the progress of Indonesia
let's share the same dream to continue to
grow
collaborate to develop potential
together
[Music]
along with the rapid development
that occurs the needs of the
Indonesian people are also increasing customers
need partners to help
achieve their life goals established since
1956 Danamon is committed to caring
and helping millions of people to achieve
prosperity not only to customers
but also to employees and the
wider community to grow together
to achieve better prosperity
through its products and services Danamon
provides control for
banking matters In order to achieve
life goals and everything remains under control
[Music]
maximize financial goals with
Danamon savings
Realize family aspirations through my
dream savings Daily transactions are
easier using Danamon credit cards
can Danamon MasterCard and
Danamon American Express expand
business with term installment credit
and business credit
maximize profits with
Max flexi savings maximize
company performance through trade  Finance
management financial Supply
runs a Sharia life with
Sharia savings, Sharia deposits and
Hajj savings, protect
your future and your family with Life Insurance,
vehicle insurance, health insurance,
property insurance, travel insurance
and employee benefits with Synergy of
local strengths, Danamon expands its
marketing network and branch offices
from Sabang to Merauke and is
supported by professional staff to
provide the best service
in line with Danamon's vision to
prosper the Indonesian people,
also reflected in various
activities through CSR activities and Amon
Run and several other activities
[Applause]
[Music]
as a result of its commitment and has
also been awarded several awards
at the world level with Synergy of
local strengths with Global networks and expertise,
Danamon is ready to present
reliable banking products and services so that
your financial affairs remain under control,
now is the time for you to take control with
Danamon,
change always presents challenges
like us who choose to continue to
adapt and transform into
Sig
We have a goal to become the
largest building material solution provider
in the region through product innovation,
we create future construction methods
that are fast,
affordable
and environmentally friendly,
we innovate by creating
more practical,
integrated and useful construction facilities
now We are a
building material solution provider company that will
act differently and always exceed
the reach  Sig gobion next
[Music]